

Profile

Motivated and forward-thinking Unity Developer with 4+ years of experience in software development. Superbly skilled at collaborating with a diverse range of people and can inspire and engage with any team to achieve results. Has the courage to take action on new opportunities and has strong commercial awareness to ensure that the risks are properly managed.

In previous roles reduced the delivery time and was able to coordinate 97% of product completion in line with the company roadmap. In the role of Product Owner, with mentorship from experienced project managers, they are now able to provide excellent business consultancy and develop software using aquired technical skills and knowledge. For example, they have used Unity to ship an iOS app, used Ionic, Vue and Node.js to create their portfolio and they have experience creating websites and landing pages commercially using bootstrap.

Employment History

Product Owner, FACE TO THE LIGHT LTD., London

NOVEMBER 2019 - PRESENT

- Providing excellent communication between business, sales and IT teams to refine the product and prioritise features based on market demands.
- Working with IT and product manager to drive the solution development process and ensure that the product team is in line with the vision.
- · Collaborating with teams to discover and deliver the best solution to the market.
- Created and maintained the solution vision, roadmap, and backlog of work through the project's life cycle.
- Translated features into user stories within the team's backlog while managing, ranking, and prioritising the backlog to reflect stakeholder's requirements.
- Effectively negotiating sprint goals with the team, resulting in faster delivery time.
- Overseeing all aspects of landing page creation, from copywriting, to UX/UI, to constant Conversion Rate Optimization through data-driven A/B tests.
- Copywriting tag lines, why buys, page headlines, digital ads, and retail signage while adhering to an authentic brand voice.
- Creating automated email campaigns; behavioral, transactional, and engagementoriented.

Product Owner, WEENGS LTD., London

APRIL 2017 - NOVEMBER 2019

- Managed their own courier and removals company. From November 2017, engaged in long term contract with Weengs Ltd order fulfilment start-up. Exceeded client's expectations and was promoted to Product Owner in January 2018.
- Further perfected the products and improved the business and contributed insights to the driver phone app testing.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to understand business problem statements and convert them into user stories.
- Articulated product vision and user stories in a way clearly understandable to development teams.
- Worked closely with developers to improve software and communicated with customer services and operation management using Slack and Asana to improve the team.
- In this warehouse environment took the lead on operational efficiency and worked closely with line managers to inspire the teams to enable better utilisation of individual's skills.
- Managed backlog of user stories for 2 products simultaneously.
- Established user story acceptance criteria and refined stories with Scrum teams.

Details

Dongguan, China

+8618670213013

greg@unlimit.co.uk

https://github.com/gregdavies91

https://linkedin.com/in/gregdavies91

NATIONALITY

British

DRIVING LICENSE

Full Clean UK

Skills

Ability to Learn New Languages

Ability to Work Under Pressure

Leadership

Agile and Scrum

Conceptual Skills

User Centred Design Process

Design Quality Standards

Analytical Skills

Collaboration & Teamwork

Communication

Customer Service

Languages

English

Chinese

French

- Created Sprint Release Plans with input from development teams.
- Applied Agile methods and processes to promote a disciplined and transparent project management process.
- Planned and estimated 2-week sprints in a realistic yet time-efficient manner that allowed the teams to deliver 97% of the MVP
 according to the company roadmap.

Operations Manager, VALLIE LTD., London

JUNE 2016 - APRIL 2017

- Updated the customer regularly through their phone app.
- Provided excellent customer service and engaged with the team to encourage as much feedback as possible to ensure customers were in good hands.
- Passed background checks.
- Regularly audited to ensure safety & excellence.
- Swiftly promoted to Operations Manager. Used Excel, Slack, Asana, "When I Work' and back office software to organise the team's scheduling and to engage with the team.
- Demonstrated their ability to manage a team and achieved results under outstanding pressure.
- Provided excellent technology, management and customer service skills.
- Generated more business for the company making sales calls.

Director, UNLIMIT LTD., Cheltenham

JUNE 2011 - APRIL 2013

- While holding this Senior post gained relevant marketing experience in an executive role as Director in partnership with the software engineer team.
- Acted as product owner in the team to develop a piece of educational music software.
- Analysed the market using a CRM and created copy to publicise and tapped into a niche market on Apple's App Store.
- Demonstrated an ability to act upon opportunities that present themselves and inspire the team to pursue ambitious targets.
- Worked alongside designers and demonstrated excellent organisational, written and verbal communication skills.

Technical / Sales Assistant, PINK-NOISE SYSTEMS LTD., Dursley

SEPTEMBER 2008 - SEPTEMBER 2009

Education

GCSEs, Pittville Performing Arts Secondary School, Cheltenham

SEPTEMBER 2002 - JUNE 2007

- A* Music
- A English Lit and Mathematics
- B English Lang, Art and Design, History, R.E., and Double Science
- · CCCC IT
- · High Attendance and Punctual
- Arts Prefect

Courses

Learn Unity - Beginner's Game Development Tutorial (Currently Studying) - freeCodeCamp

NOVEMBER 2021

Unity Essentials (Currently Studying) - Unity

NOVEMBER 2021

C# (Currently Studying) - Sololearn

NOVEMBER 2021

Python (Currently Studying) - Mimo

SEPTEMBER 2021

Intro To Vue 3 - Vue Mastery

AUGUST 2021

Grasshopper Coding Fundamentals I & II - Google

AUGUST 202

5 Day Coding Challenge - Code Institute

JULY 2021